# XUN CHEN

330 Crescent Village Cir. San Jose, CA xunchen369@gmail.com +1(973)-767-9194 www.xunchen.me

## **ABOUT ME**

Creative Front-End Engineer with strong engineering background, specialized in Front-End architecture, Data Visualization, and User Interface Design. I like to inspire myself by learning new technologies, perfecting techniques through constant practice and applying them for innovation.

## **SKILLS**

Image/Vector Graphics Editing
Wireframing
UI Design
Data Visualization
Web Development
Front-End Testing
Command Line
VIM Editor

# **TECHNOLOGIES**

ES5,ES6,ES7 SCSS Node.js ReactJS Redux/Redux-Thunk/Redux-Saga D3.js Three.js Webpack/Gulp/Grunt Jest Git Sketch/Illustrator/Photoshop

## **LANGUAGE**

English Chinese

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### TARGET, SUNNYVALE, CA

Apr 2016 - May 2018

Lead Data Engineer

- Designed and implemented UI/UX wireframes and mock ups using Sketch, Photoshop and Illustrator
- Developed Several Data Visualization Web based Dashboards using D3.js, Angular 1.X and ReactJS.
- Spearheaded the architecture, design, feature of a generalized log streaming platform web based user interface.
- Mentored other front-end engineers and consulted for other teams at Target.
- Implemented and contributed to tools that aided Front-End Development at Target.

#### **AKUDA LABS, SAN JOSE, CA**

Jul 2015 - Apr 2016

Software Engineer

- Developed a query based full-stack web application that allows cross cluster queries of Elastic Search indices.
- Programmed a Tableau Web Data Connector to connect Tableau with our internal API calls.
- Built a web application that visualizes geo location data, sentiment data, and traffic from social media on the topics of the 2016 election using Node.js, AngularJS, and D3.js.

#### **DELPHI, SHANGHAI, CHINA**

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

R&D Software Intern

- Implemented a web application that allows users to tune into various radio channels from www.qingting.fm for Delphi's automobile infotainment system using Sencha Touch.
- Used RESTFUL API to retrieve live radio streaming data from Qingting's internal API using a PHP backend.

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# SHANGHAI WORLD EXPO 2010, SHANGHAI, CHINA

Jun 2010 - Jul 2010

Chinese/English Translator

 Volunteered at a service stand as a translator and guide for visitors of the Shanghai World EXPO 2010.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign**

Aug 2011 - May 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

# **INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES**

Piano
Table Tennis
Traveling
Stock Trading
Graphic Design
Desktop Widget Development
PC Customization